Welcome back. Your Grace.
I take it you had a good flight?
-I'm knackered.
-Mm.
-Has she started?
-Uh. she has.
My new associate Deandra
will have your bags
brought to your suite
while you're in the café.
Ah. Of course.
We'll take care of it.
Yes. taking a chance on love.
which is what you did
when you made your reservation
six months ago.
But it already seems worth it.
doesn't it?
Seeing me up close.
in the flesh.
an award-winning
cabaret artiste.
-One award.
-Excuse me. Jolly?
You've won one award.
Most people hear
"award-winning."
they think "several."
Thanks for the clarification.
Bitch.
It's true.
I've won only one statue.
and I happen to have it with me.
Do you want to see it?
Yes.
No. it's not the Emmy
for my guest spot
on Father Crime.
which airs tonight.
This is my 1987
Mabel Short Cabaret
Performer of the Year Award.
Thank you.
So. you are seeing
a legitimate
cabaret performer. maybe
the last one in existence.
You know. the minute
they drag me out of here.
some reality star will start
squawking Sondheim.
So. let's make the most
of this night. shall we?
Isn't she fantastic?
Damn it!
What is it?
No!
Don't tell me.
I love it
when she gets like this.
Oh. And the tempo
on "Sunny Side of the Street"
was too bright.
What part of "sunny side"
don't you understand?
Don't get fresh.
And don't correct me
in the middle of a show.
You asked.
Especially when I ask.
It's no wonder I went up
with all the latecomers
and schmoozers in here.
Nobody knows
the pressure I'm under.
And I'm on the tube tonight.
We heard.
You told everybody.
I'm gonna watch upstairs.
I'll be back down
for the second show.
Have them send my dinner up
through room service.
They charge for that. you know.
What are you implying?
Oh. right there's fine.
I'm on Father Crime tonight.
Do you watch that show?
-Not since they
killed off Felicity.
-Oh.
Wow.
You guys have
raised prices again.
Put it on my tab.
Oh. wait.
Here.
Oh.
I don't have any cash.
I'll get you next time.
Want some company. guv'nor?
I know why you're here.
and it's not going to work.
I can be very persuasive.
you know.
I have to protect
my Manhattan investments.
The royal family
is under tremendous scrutiny.
We can't get away
with anything.
Exactly.
The deal smells.
and if you agree to it.
you'll be in big trouble
when everything goes south.
I've made up my mind.
This place is due for a change.
Why does anything
have to change?
Just give it a little more time.
-I'll see you out.
-No. no.
-no. no. no. no. no. no.
-Come on.
Stop. now.
Stop!
Good God. woman.
Are you mad?
Something like that.
Yes.
it's true.
I've won only one statue.
and I happen to have it with me.
- Do you want to see it?
- Yes!
Let's see it!
Whip it out!
You know what?
I don't do this for the awards.
I do it for the money.
So I'll just keep singing.
Oh.
Hello. I'm looking
for the. um... Oh.
Wow. this place is so elegant.
Uh. sorry.
I'm here for the. um...
-Possible crime scene?
-Oh. Yes.
- That's all right. I got this.
- Captain Wagner.
I was expecting
to see a detective.
Uh. since I got passed over
for commissioner.
I figured I'd get out
of the office a bit.
Oh. it's a beautiful place
for an investigation.
-Thanks.
-The Reilly is
a New York institution.
This place still looks the same
as the night
I proposed to Claudia.
right there in the café.
No wonder you're
in such a good mood.
Hey. you should be. too.
given the news.
What news?
"Mayor Bloom. seen last night
having dinner with
a mysterious brunette."
That's not a phony story
planted by Nadine.
The "mysterious redhead"
is officially yesterday's news.
You must be relieved.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Yay.
Housekeeping found him
this morning.
It looks like he slipped
getting out of the shower.
Apparently. he grabbed the towel
bar. but it came off the wall.
leaving him to smash his head
on the tile.
Oh. please. sir.
don't touch anything.
Oh. right. Sorry.
Force of habit.
Uh. what were you about to do?
Oh. we like the seams on
our lampshades to face the wall.
Excuse me. sir.
Uh. e-excuse me.
Oh.
Whoa.
Everything is just so.
with the hotel monogram
on everything.
Such a lovely old-world touch.
It's like stepping back in time.
Yeah. wow.
It's like he lived here.
Oh. he did.
Part of the time he kept
this place as a pied-à-terre.
Oh. that's right.
I forget that some people
-actually live in hotels.
-Mm-hmm.
Huh. These pajamas are folded.
and these are on a hanger.
-Well. maybe he was planning
on wearing those.
-Ooh.
Is that blood?
Maybe from a scuffle
that knocked over the lamp?
Or it could be from shaving.
Oh. This shoehorn is kind of
bent out of shape.
Nobody has that much trouble
putting on their loafers.
-Yeah. not usually.
-Hmm.
It's just in here.
What was that about?
Oh. Roger came to draw
the Duke's bath.
They had an arrangement for him
to do so whenever he was here.
He took morning baths?
Then why was he taking
a nighttime shower?
We'll need to get
as much information as we can
from your staff.
You said that the towel bar
just came off the wall?
Has anything like that
ever happened
-at the Hotel Reilly before?
-Well. not recently.
We've had some incidents
of wear and tear.
but that's why
we've begun renovations.
including this very suite.
This bathroom was remodeled
six months ago.
So it's very possible
that somebody
broke it off on purpose
and made it look
like an accident.
But how?
I've never seen
anything like this.
and I've worked at the Reilly
for 29 years.
Oh. you must have
so many stories.
Oh. we all do.
Uh. but we're discreet.
which is exactly what I told
Julia Roberts and Ted Kennedy.
-We appreciate it.
-Well. let me know
whatever you need.
and. um. uh.
if you can't reach me.
you can speak
to my associate Deandra.
Hello.
De-- Uh. what did you say
your name was again?
Um. because you remind me
of a woman I once met
named Denise Jackson.
Well. I'm Deandra Jordan.
Any questions you have.
come to me.
In the meantime.
if you'd like
some complimentary coffee. tea.
or juice. please help yourself.
Thank you.
Who's that?
It's Ruby Lane.
She performs in the café.
lives upstairs.
Wait. the Ruby Lane?
She's still around?
You're out of stevia.
That should not happen
at a decent hotel.
I apologize.
It's been a difficult morning.
Yes. uh. one of the residents.
Duke Sebastian.
slipped in the shower and died.
My God. How tragic.
No surprise.
I'll go let the kitchen know
about the stevia shortage.
This whole place
is falling apart.
Something like this
was bound to happen again.
I just said he slipped
in the shower.
not that there was
any physical damage.
Mm. I assumed.
It's all breaking down.
My room-- you have
to jiggle the handle.
You two should come
and see my show.
If you can afford the cover
charge and the two-drink minimum
on a cop's salary.
I'm a captain.
Yeah. but I'll save up.
Oh. hey. I have that very tote.
Well. somewhere
in my collection.
Bye.
Oh. you asked for more
information from housekeeping.
It seems some of the more
expensive items were missing
from the Duke's minibar.
including
the yogurt-covered raisins.
Ooh. I love those.
But there was no sign of them
in the trash.
Well. who would murder someone
and walk off
with the goodies
from the minibar?
Hmm.
Oh. my God.
it's like you're in every story.
Teddy. What are you doing here?
Well. um. I have some news.
Maybe. I think so.
But if you're reading
about Alec's new girlfriend.
-it can wait.
-Oh. uh...
Whoever she is.
she has my sympathy.
-You sure?
-Positive.
So. um. what is your news.
maybe. you think so?
Well. um. Roy and I
may be getting married.
What?
-Teddy.
-Yeah.
- Oh. I'm so happy.
- Ah!
- Well. I said maybe. Um...
- Okay.
But we did have a conversation
that felt like it.
though we changed subjects
-because I started
hyperventilating.
-Oh.
Well. I am thrilled.
to the extent
that it's more than maybe.
Yeah. but the thing is.
I'm pretty sure Roy wants me
to propose because
I'm basically allergic
-to overt romantic gestures.
-That is true.
but have no fear.
I have so many ideas.
-Uh...
-Okay. Did you know
that you can order skywriting
over Times Square?
Yeah. no. Um. I was thinking
something lower-key. Like. um.
during the finale of a show
that we're watching on Thursday.
sharing a frozen Hawaiian pizza
with a thrift store ring
hidden under a piece
of Canadian bacon.
Sometimes I forget that.
in some ways.
you do take after your father.
who proposed to me
in a footnote in a legal brief.
Okay. um...
Well. what-what if I cooked for
him. just the way you taught me?
Yeah... what else you got?
You know what? It's gonna be
fine. even without your help.
So I will. uh.
let you know how it goes.
-Oh.
-Oh. God.
We're really
gonna do this. maybe.
And this is our business center.
We can talk in here.
-Why in the business center?
-Oh. nobody ever uses it.
- Oh.
- So. start from the beginning.
Right. This hotel has been
engaged in shady bookkeeping
and tax fraud since it was built
during Prohibition.
Wow. that is the beginning.
And with Alec Bloom
as the new mayor
promising greater scrutiny.
the current owner
Havenford Realty Group--
they want out.
But any sale depends on approval
from the long-term residents.
The Duke came back to New York
to cast his vote.
but after what happened.
the vote has been postponed.
Any idea who the buyer is?
Havenford isn't saying.
It's part of my mission
to find out. but my guess is.
it's one of the mysterious
guests staying here this week.
I've spotted a mob boss.
a Saudi sheik.
and a Russian oligarch.
but I can't be sure.
And you think the Duke
could have been murdered
-because of his vote?
-I don't know.
but the timing is suspicious.
Ruby Lane would have a vote.
She lives here.
Could she be involved
in those financial schemes?
You mean the lady
who steals two gallons
of lobby coffee every morning
and who can't remember
her lyrics?
-I doubt it.
-All right.
I think I'll have some lunch
in the hotel lobby bar
and interview the guests.
Are you sure
you're not just trying
to soak up the atmosphere?
I can do both.
Uh. hey. do you happen
to know what floor
Ruby Lane lives on?
-You have a good eye.
-Oh.
I don't know about that.
I just like beautiful things.
And dogs.
The exquisite Reilly murals
once belonged to the Blick
family of the Blick Museum.
I happen to be very close
to several Blicks.
Montgomery Blakemont III.
art connoisseur and
philanthropist. Call me Monty.
Hi. Monty.
Elsbeth Tascioni.
Consent decree lawyer
with the NYPD.
I'm talking art appreciation
with the fuzz.
How fantastic is that?
Pretty fantastic.
This hotel is filled
with great art.
but not all of it
in public spaces.
There are treasures to be found
-in certain suites.
-Wow.
-You seem to know so much.
-I do.
-I keep a place here.
-Oh.
Were you here
when the Duke died?
Oh. yes. I was in the café.
-Oh.
-Uh. in the first show.
Ruby forgot her lyrics.
it was epic.
And then. at
the late show. she was on fire.
You went to the café
twice in one night?
-Mm.
-That's a four-drink minimum.
Isn't that expensive?
Excuse me. Ah.
It's the Metropolitan Museum.
I'm gifting them $20 million.
and we're arguing
over the size
of my name on the plaque.
-Can you imagine?
-No.
This is Monty. Are you ready
to talk some sense?
Okay. great.
Thank you.
Oh. hello again.
-Aren't you getting in?
-Oh. no.
Uh. actually.
I-I changed my mind.
Oh. Well. suit yourself.
Excuse me. I have to rehearse.
You still need to rehearse
after all these years?
Well. I don't need to.
but I dropped something
the other night.
and Jolly. my accompanist.
got his knickers in a twist.
Oh.
Um. is there any chance
-that I could sit in and watch?
-No.
Oh. please?
I-I-It would be so fascinating
to watch a legend at work.
Do you go to nightclubs a lot?
Uh. no. that's just the thing.
I know so little about cabaret
as an art form.
Um. is it anything like Glee?
Are you for real?
You mean am I... serious?
Absolutely.
Although... I am really here
with the police.
helping them
with their murder investigation.
Yes. taking a chance on love.
which is what you did
when you made your reservation
six months ago.
Blah. blah. blah.
We do that whole bit.
Oh. so we're not
just winging it?
I forgot. I said I was sorry.
Hey. Little Orphan Annie.
what do you think so far?
You're incredible.
You make every word
so... specific.
It's like. uh. it's like
you're singing just to me.
Well. I mean. uh.
you are right now.
but it's like...
you're speaking to my soul.
She gets it.
Cabaret is the most intimate
form of communication.
Up here.
there's nowhere to hide.
The lights. the proximity
expose everything.
Believe me. what I do...
is not about a beautiful voice.
Oh. we believe you.
- Ignore him. The way I do
when he falls down in a gutter.
You two are so funny.
How long have you two
been working together?
Let's see. next month
it will have been an eternity.
- But it's worth it
to show up every night
and dream of getting paid.
Including two shows last night.
-As usual.
-What do you do between shows?
-I have dinner in here.
-Except the night before last.
You mean the night
the Duke died?
Oh. right. That night I wanted
to watch myself on the tube.
I recently shot a guest spot
on Father Crime.
Oh. I know that show.
Wow. you must be
a great actress.
Father Crime gets
the best guest stars.
probably because
it shoots in New York.
I was great.
and I had room service.
Speaking of food. you probably
need lunch. don't you?
Cherie. bring this lovely lady
a Waldorf salad.
and bring one for me
while you're at it.
-Thank you. Cherie. but...
-It's the best thing they do.
You'll love it.
And you'll need your strength.
investigating that...
-Did you say it was
a murder investigation?
-Mm-hmm.
Duke Sebastian Mason.
Lord of Sussexford.
Did-did you know him?
No. but I heard he was
at my show the night he died.
-Not a bad way to go.
-I'll say.
Especially if you made
the reservation
six months earlier.
You have a cute personality.
Do you sing?
Me? Oh. gosh. no. no.
But. um. my son Teddy--
he has a beautiful voice.
He could be on Broadway.
but he's too shy.
He recently told me
he may be getting married.
-Really? Congratulations.
-Thanks.
To be honest.
I'm a little nervous about it.
Yeah. I'm afraid
he-he might pull away.
I'm wondering. you know.
how I'll handle that.
Oh. I love that song.
I think that's my favorite song
by Irving Berlin.
I thought you knew nothing
about cabaret.
Oh. I don't.
But I know
the Great American Songbook.
I'm not a monster.
I don't like your act. sister.
It's phony.
Cherie. send my lunch upstairs.
and charge it to her.
You've got a lot of nerve.
Elsbeth.
With all the things in the world
to get worked up about...
Is it the drinking?
I noticed she has a glass
in her hand in all the photos.
That's just a prop to give her
a false air of sophistication.
Hers is always filled
with water. unlike mine.
So. when she forgets
her lyrics...
Ms. Tascioni. come quick.
- Oh.
What is it?
Housekeeping heard someone
inside the Duke's suite.
So you think the killer returned
to the scene of the crime?
Whoever's in there. open up.
This is the police.
Oh. hey. you.
Mr. Blakemont. we have learned
from someone at the hotel
that your name doesn't appear
on any suite here at the hotel.
Was it that new woman Deandra?
She seems on the ball.
Why are you hanging
around the hotel?
All right. if you must know.
I'm staying in a suite
that's owned by a former boss
but only while my townhouse
is being renovated.
And does your former boss know?
Of course he does. technically.
But don't worry.
all of my employers
trust me implicitly.
That's why they give me
power of attorney.
But what were you doing here
in the Duke's suite?
I was looking at the artwork.
In a dead man's room?
As I told Elsbeth.
not all of the art at the Reilly
is publicly displayed.
This room
has an Edward Hopper
plus a tiny Titian.
It's true. He did tell me that.
Well. you're still a suspect.
And since you're such an expert
on the Hotel Reilly.
what do you know about that vote
to approve a sale?
I know everything about it. My
former boss made me his proxy.
Of course he did.
Which way do you think
it would have gone?
Oh. it was split
right down the middle.
The in-favor side insisted
the Duke come for the vote
to put them over the top.
It was very exciting.
-Why? Why did it matter so much?
-Well.
rumor is. the mystery buyer
planned a major.
very tasteful renovation.
but to pay for it.
they were gonna have
to clean up the books.
so that meant that
the long-term residents
would have to settle up
their maintenance.
rents. bar tabs.
Some of these people
have been getting away
with murder
while guzzling the free coffee.
-Mm.
-And what about you?
Eh... how were you gonna vote?
I was in favor. all the way.
I encouraged the others.
Here. let me see my phone.
I'll show you.
I have a thing
about freeloaders.
By the way.
the hotel Wi-Fi is pretty weak.
but I have the code
to the Sephora next door.
Roy. To what
do I owe the pleasure?
I have some news. Well. maybe.
Teddy and I
may be getting married.
Oh. that is so great.
I am so happy.
I mean. maybe.
We had a conversation about it.
but then Teddy
started hyperventilating.
Oh. yeah. he does that.
But before anything happens.
I wanted to come
and ask your permission.
Oh. Roy. Of course.
- Yes.
- Okay.
I didn't know
you were so traditional.
That's why I want
a super romantic proposal scene.
and we both know
Teddy will never.
-Mm.
-What can I say?
I'm old-fashioned.
brought up in the suburbs.
repressed but very performative.
Teddy better get used to it.
Uh. wait.
Does that mean
that you and Teddy
might move to the suburbs
eventually?
Probably. I mean. I love
New York. but I want kids.
Oh.
Okay. I still think
she's too much of a train wreck
to kill anybody.
but I did some digging
into Ruby's account.
It's true. she is in arrears.
but my friend in bookkeeping
hasn't told me how much yet.
Oh. there you are. Deandra.
-I need you.
-Coming.
-Excuse me.
-Uh-huh.
Now can we do a more formal
interview with her?
I suppose. And it might be
interesting to see her suite.
Ah. I bet it's pretty glamorous.
Oh. sorry. it's such a mess.
If I'd known you were coming.
I would have been out.
-How long have you lived here?
-Who knows?
I paid $28.000 for it.
if it gives you an idea.
Wow.
And how do you feel
about the possible sale?
I was mad they postponed.
I was voting yes.
-You were?
-Hell yes.
I'm ready to sell.
I'm tired of New York.
I want to go someplace
where I'm not so damn famous.
Maybe if you didn't walk around
in a mink coat and sunglasses.
people wouldn't recognize you.
Just a thought.
I get cold. Here. Snacks.
Ooh. yogurt-covered raisins.
-Funny. these were missing
from the Duke's minibar.
-Yeah?
Well. I take them
from the housekeepers' carts
in the hallway.
This place owes me that much.
I'm a legend.
Yes. you are.
But that's why
I don't understand
why you want to leave here now.
at this point.
Why? Because I'm gonna die soon?
No. because you're
such a fixture here.
This city is too run-down.
It's like...
everything was better
when I was younger. you know?
Or maybe you just get to an age
where you hate everything.
Where are you going to go?
Someplace more elegant--
Vegas. Florida. Phoenix.
And. uh. what about
the money you owe?
What money?
We happen to know
that you're in arrears
-on your maintenance.
-Oh.
Well. selling this place
will take care of all that
and then some.
Now. if you don't have any more
-questions...
-No. no. no. One more thing.
Where were you on the night
of Duke Sebastian's murder?
I already told your friend.
I came up here between shows
to watch myself in a guest role
- on Father Crime.
- Woo-hoo.
I haven't seen this week's
episode yet. What did you play?
I played a nun in a story
about a Mother Superior.
a murderous Mother Superior.
I sang a song
to a bunch of orphans.
-How did it go?
-Not bad.
It really looked like
I was playing the guitar.
So many shows
tell stories about nuns.
Hair and makeup is a breeze.
Ooh. I love index cards.
What are these for?
Those are my contacts. I used
to keep. um. an address book
but kept losing it.
and I use code
so the housekeepers don't call
all my celebrity friends.
Oh. that's smart. I love a code.
Um. "Figaro" for my hairdresser.
"Brontë" for my sister.
"Kid" for Michael Feinstein.
Oh. Who's "Vernon"?
My nephew. One of my nephews.
Grandnephew.
And he is grand.
That looked like
an international number.
He works overseas. I miss him.
I-I don't mean to be rude.
but I do have two shows tonight
and I have to go on vocal rest.
Thanks for your time.
Oh. Mm.
Bye.
She threw you out?
-Pretty much.
-Well. that's Ruby.
Now. this mural is my favorite
work of art at the Hotel Reilly.
The artist Pierre Montclair
worked on it for years.
His daughter Ellie
still lives here.
-You'll know it's her.
She wears Coke-bottle glasses.
-Aw.
Apparently. it's filled
with inside jokes.
- See the two trombone players?
- Mm-hmm.
The Fortunato Brothers
were twins
who played here for years.
And that couple dancing?
That's Harold.
a former bartender.
and Sylvie from laundry.
They were married
to other people.
Oh. goodness.
Ellie has permission
to add to the mural
when something important
happens here.
-That's nice.
-Mm.
-Is Ruby Lane anywhere?
-Oh. sure. Yeah.
She's right here.
She told Pierre she'd have
to be carried out of here
- feet first.
- Huh.
That's not what she told us.
There you are. Psst.
My friend in bookkeeping
came through.
Take a look at what Ruby owes.
Oh. my Lord.
- That's in dollars?
- A lot of them.
Huh. And plenty of reason
for Ruby
-to do anything to stay here.
-Mm-hmm.
Mother Abigail.
Is Father Garvey right?
Did you kill that pop star?
Of course not.
Then swear. To God.
I can't.
-Huh.
-What are you watching?
Oh. Hey. Uh. this week's episode
of Father Crime.
You pay for that
streaming service?
What? No. Just a free trial.
So. what'd you want
to talk to me about?
Well...
I really think that you should
do something more romantic
when you propose to Roy.
no matter how much
you love frozen pizza.
I don't really want to do
a big thing.
Yes. but you also don't want Roy
to feel disappointed.
I knew this was gonna happen
if I told you.
You've gotten in my head.
Why are you doing this?
Is it because you don't think
I'm mature enough
to get married?
What? No. And maturity
is not a requirement.
You know. sometimes maybe
it's not such a bad thing
that I'm more like Dad.
I doubt that.
Because Roy isn't marrying you.
He's marrying me.
And I don't want him
to get a false sense
of what life with me
is going to be like. You know?
There's gonna be more nights
of TV and pizza
than there is flowers
and skywriting.
Why are people
so against skywriting?
-Chemtrails.
-Those aren't real.
Fine. I'll stay out of it.
Too late!
-Hey.
Hey. Teddy.
What's going on?
Nothing. I just...
Do you remember how you proposed
to your wife?
Do I remember?
It cost me two weeks of salary.
but it was worth every penny.
I... still have that...
champagne cork
sitting on my dresser.
And to this day. every year.
on our anniversary. Claudia...
tells the kids about that night.
She remembers every detail.
and so do they.
Oh. you should see
the way her eyes...
light up when she even
thinks about it.
I think I just did.
No. I said stevia.
Yes. ma'am.
Hello.
Would you. uh.
care for some company?
Suit yourself.
Ah. Thank you.
I watched your episode
of Father Crime.
You were very good.
Oh. thank you.
But I kept waiting for the song
that you said you sang
to the orphans.
It wasn't in the episode.
-I guess it got cut.
-Right.
But you said you watched it
the night of the murder.
I'm old. I must have confused
what we shot
and what they used.
Sue me.
It's not out of character.
Right.
And you definitely
are a character.
That must be exhausting
sometimes.
to be the way you are. just
to keep your place
in the city's... zeitgeist.
I wasn't always like this.
and I wasn't always alone.
I was married.
Herman had a...
...had a bagel company.
We had a lot of laughs.
He died too young
and left me enough
to buy that dump upstairs.
After that. I realized...
the only way to survive
being an older woman
in this city
is to be... memorable.
Not just yesterday's news.
Oh. it's. um...
nice chatting with you.
I have a hair appointment.
See you around. Elsbeth.
That sounds familiar.
It's "September Song."
- For me. it's a long while
from May to October.
It's from a show called
Knickerbocker Holiday.
Oh. What was the show about?
It was a musical comedy
about fascism.
It wasn't very popular.
but it gets revived
every once in a while.
The music is so beautiful...
and sad.
Kurt Weill.
He wrote it a few years
after fleeing the Nazis.
He figured people
are safe in America.
Maybe that's why
it sounds so sad.
So the Great American Songbook
isn't just American. is it?
Oh. no. Some of our
best composers
came through Ellis Island
on the way to Tin Pan Alley.
Irving Berlin. Vernon Duke.
-Igor Stravinsky.
-Wait.
Vernon Duke?
"Vernon" was on the index card
above Ruby's bed.
It must've been code
for Duke Sebastian.
whom she claimed she didn't
know. She definitely knew him.
Jolly. was there
anything different
about the second show
that night?
Was Ruby distracted
or out of breath?
She seemed happy.
which was different.
Oh. and she changed
that one bit.
-What bit?
-She didn't take out
her Mabel Short Award.
She said she forgot to bring it.
but when I placed
the tote bag onstage.
it weighed the same as always.
Like Ruby said. "The lights.
the proximity
expose everything."
Hey. do you mind?
I'm working.
Ruby Lane. you're under arrest
for the murder
of Duke Sebastian Mason.
Lord of Sussexford.
- That's absurd.
- It did seem so.
but we now know you owe
this hotel so much money.
you could not let the Duke vote
to approve the sale.
So you lied.
pretending you didn't know him.
but you had
his phone number taped
to your wall.
We found it in your trash.
And your alibi was shaky.
You pretended that you watched
your episode of Father Crime.
but you didn't know
they'd cut your song.
And don't forget
the yogurt-covered raisins
from the minibar.
How could we?
All that proves nothing.
I'm old.
drunk. outrageous.
I get confused.
No. I don't think you do.
See. I think you pretend
to drink and forget your lyrics
-to make yourself memorable.
-It's working.
But you're right.
it is all
circumstantial
without the murder weapon.
Now. I figured that
you used the shoehorn
from the Duke's closet
to pry off the towel bar
and then make it look like a...
slip-and-fall accident.
But the Duke's room
wasn't as decrepit as yours.
so you had to find something
heavy to use as a hammer.
Like that award
you carry around.
-Can anyone follow this?
-It's not that hard.
But the base of your
Mabel Short Award is.
After you used it
to kill the Duke
and then hammer off the
towel bar. you came back here...
...to the second show.
only this time
you cut the bit
where you take the award
out of your tote. which. um.
really upset Jolly.
I'm a creature of habit
and professionalism.
You didn't take it out
because you realized
the stage lights and the
proximity to the audience
would have exposed any blood
or other evidence.
so you waited
until after the show
where you could
wash it all away.
-That is a wild accusation.
-Yes. but
we can prove it. All we need
to do is examine your award.
Well. you can't.
You don't have a warrant.
And this is mine.
See. I told you
I do have a tote
just like that one.
Oh. dear. did I take
the wrong one?
You may have washed it off.
but there. clear as day.
are the imprints
from the shoehorn handle.
They really do monogram
everything at this hotel.
It's like stepping back in time.
It looks like the gig
is finally up.
You have the right
to remain silent.
That's all right.
I know the words.
See. I knew you were lying
when you said
you wanted to leave New York.
How could anybody want to leave?
Feet first.
I wonder what's gonna happen
to this place.
I don't understand. The sign
said the place is closed.
Yeah. for a private event.
That's us.
Shall I bring the first course?
Not yet.
I'm gonna do something
before I lose my nerve.
What are you...?
Oh. my God.
It's true.
He could be on Broadway.
Right?
I still have the cork
sitting on my dresser.
Teddy's getting married.
Yeah.
It happened so fast.
Hey. You okay?
Yeah. I'm okay.
-Oh.
-It's just the end of one season
and the beginning of another.
I know things will change.
and maybe they'll move
to the suburbs.
but no matter what...
I'm not gonna miss out
on being a grandmother
because my clothes are so soft
-and they're gonna love my hugs.
-Hey.
Slow down.
You have nothing to worry about.
Teddy's a mama's boy.
And you are never gonna change.
That's why people love you.
It's gonna be hard
to leave this place.
For me. too.
I was just getting used
to Deandra.
They like me so much.
I'm being promoted
to work for the
Havenford Group office.
Captain Kershaw thinks
it's a smart move.
I kind of like it when you
pop up in surprising places.
-Hmm.
-Hey. Did you ever figure out
who was trying to buy the hotel?
Hmm.
Hey. did you see that?
Oh. I love that show.
Wasn't it wonderful?
It was so great. I cried.
Yeah. me. too.
Isn't it great to love things?